Diego Thon Cortés

Front-End Developer

CONTACT

+ (56) 9 84137867 diegothoncortes@gmail.com

SKILLS

CSS (scss-less)
Bootstrap
Tailwind (Beginner)
Angular Material
JavaScript
Angular
ReactJS (Beginner)
Firebase
Git
NodeJS (Beginner)

Spanish (Native)
English (C1 Advanced)

CERTIFICATIONS

EF Standard English Test (EF SET)

ABOUT ME

Web developer, with 3 years of experience in programming languages, tools and frameworks, mainly performing the role of Semi-senior programmer.

My IT background includes Front-end development on web platforms.

All this making use of agile methodologies when addressing projects, particularly with Scrum methodology.

Within my skills I highlight pro-activity, self-taught, and desire to learn new things within the field of IT and web development

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Front-End Developer (Soho)

6/2022 - Current

- Redesign of the graphic interface on web platforms, proposed by the user (Gasco, Zurich, Banco Itau).
- Integration of external APIs for online payments such as Webpay and Zumpago (Khipu, Mach, ETpay, Check).
- Maintaining well-documented code for future changes or improvements.
- Utilization of Flexbox and @Media queries for responsiveness and adaptability across different viewports.
- Framework used: Angular 11.
- Proficiency in Jira and Kanban board for task management, and Confluence for documentation.
- Creation and modification of components using Stencil.
- Proficient in managing repositories on BitBucket.

Front-End Developer (Everis NTT DATA)

1/2021 - 6/2022

- Updating and redesigning the graphic interface of web platforms or desktop applications proposed by the user (LATAM Airlines, Clínica Alemana).
- Updating services and HTTP queries for API consumption.
- Maintaining well-organized code for future changes or improvements.
- Creating layouts with HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap for various projects.
- Full front-end development using Angular Material for the Latam Flight Availability project (DispoOnline).
- Frameworks used: Angular 12+, ReactJS.
- Proficient in using Jira and Kanban board for task management.
- Managing repositories on BitBucket, GitLab.
- Experience with cloud platforms such as GCP and AWS (both parallel projects).

Front-End Developer (Municipal Corporation)

5/2019 - 12/2019

- Development of an application to streamline the sale of plots in the municipal cemetery of Pozo Almonte.
- Framework used: Angular 7.

EDUCATION

Inacap Valdivia, Chile (University)

- Computer engineering, 2012 - 2018

2019 - Graduated

2019 - Licensed